Construction of a Sigma-Based Benchmarking Chart
Welcome back to this session on benchmarking. Recall,
we took a look at the error rate in a unit of product and the total number of units produced.
And was able to ascertain the unit error rate.
We took that number. Divided it by the number of opportunities per unit.
In this case it was four. This was the number of critical to quality characteristics
that was present in that unit of product or service.
Things that must be right about that unit or service.
And what we found is there were 50 of those things that weren’t right.
So, that gives us an opportunity error rate of .0125.
A thousand units at four opportunities per unit is 4,000 defect opportunities produced.
50 divided by 4,000 is .0125.
With that 0125, we get our DPMO, with the DPMO, we get our Sigma capability.
Now, a simpler way to do that is to have a little graph here. Now, it’s pretty cool.
What this is. You can make these in Excel
or anywhere and we’ll be zooming in here to look specifically at these graphs.
So, I will have a logarithmic scale moving
on the vertical axis here. If we zoom in here real close.
Let's look at what we mean by a log scale. We’re going to go real tight here.
So, we can make this big. I mean really big.
Okay. Notice here is one and here's ten.
See these lines, how to get closer, and closer, and closer, together.
Well, this is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Then it progresses by another 10. This now goes 10, 20, 30, 40, 60, 80, 100.
This now goes 100, 200, 300, 400 to a 1,000.
1,000, 2,000, 3,000 to 10,000. That's a logarithmic scale.
And what we’re going to do is simply take our calculation.
Recall from here, 12,500 DPMO. Locate it here
on this graph, project over
to the intersect, to this transfer line, and project down
to the Sigma scale.
And what we see is the intersect is 3.74 Sigma.
The same thing that we got from converting 12,500 defects per million opportunities
through a conversion table to a Sigma value. We’re just doing it graphically.
Converting 12,500
to the Sigma scale.
And one of the things that we’re going to do, is do that for all of our key processes.
We’re going to find where the defect rates are
for our key processes, project down and get the Sigmas.
And then look at the range in which they fall. That's how we go about benchmarking.
Now, as we move forward with that thinking.
What I want to do is show you a few simple benchmarks.
Let's take a look at this. Again, we have the same kind of chart.
Defects per million opportunities. We have Sigma scale of measure.
And, I want you look at some of these actual real-life benchmarks.
Here’s airline baggage handling, running about Four Sigma, as you can see.
Or about 6,800 defects per million opportunities.
Number of U.S. incarcerations. That's a scary thought.
And here's the airline flight fatality rate at about 6.2 Sigma. Somewhere in there.
Well notice this. This level of quality at Six Sigma.
Coming over here at Six Sigma and the airline baggage handling at about Four Sigma.
That's a 1,826 time difference.
Now, what’s that really telling me?
That says the next time you go get on an airplane, you are about 1,826 times
more likely to reach your destination than your bags.
That's the difference between Four Sigma and Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.